Guide to the Amsterdam News photograph archive, Series A. Subject Files K-O, 1920-2012.
Amsterdam News photograph archive
- Series A. Subject Files
  - Subject Files O
    - Odom, Johnny "Blue Moon" (Box A-91, Folder 49)
    - Odom, Juanita (Box A-91, Folder 50)
      Print is a Polaroid. Also one velox print.
    - Odom, Retha (Box A-91, Folder 51)
      Print has press release and promotional flier attached with paperclip.
      Photographer if identified: E.S. Lowe Media
    - Odom, Sylvester (Rev.) (Box A-91, Folder 52)
      Photographer if identified: R & L Associates
    - Odom, Wilma T. (Box A-91, Folder 53)
    - O'Dwyer, Paul (Box A-91, Folder 54)
      One print has typescript leaf stapled to verso. Also two velox prints.
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Alfredo Valente, Isaac Berez
    - Odyssey (Box A-91, Folder 55)
    - Odyssey House (Box A-91, Folder 56)
      Photographer if identified: Lorenzo Tucker, L. St. Clair Dummett
    - O'Farrell, Edna T. (Box A-91, Folder 57)
    - Ofay Watcher, The (Box A-91, Folder 58)
    - Offering, The (Box A-91, Folder 59)
    - Office of Minority Enterprise (Box A-91, Folder 60)
    - Office of Minority Enterprise (Box A-91, Folder 61)
    - Offult, Walter P. (Rev.) (Box A-91, Folder 62)
    - Offult, Walter P. Jr. (Rev.) (Box A-91, Folder 63)
      Photographer if identified: Cecil Layne, King Photographers
    - Offult, William (Box A-91, Folder 64)
    - Ogbu, Edwin (Box A-91, Folder 65)
    - Ogburn, John (Rev. + Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 66)
    - Oglesbry, Thomas E. (Box A-91, Folder 67)
    - Ogletree, Janice (Box A-91, Folder 68)
    - O'Grady, Joseph E. (Box A-91, Folder 69)
    - Ogunleye, Bisi (Chief) (Box A-91, Folder 70)
    - O'Hagen, John T. (Box A-91, Folder 71)
      Photographer if identified: FDNY Photo/Fr. J. Biondi
    - O'Hara, A.C. (Maj. Gen.) (Box A-91, Folder 72)
      Photographer if identified: James Houlihan
    - Ohiki, Obiageli (Box OS-1, Folder 2)
    - Ohio Players (Box A-91, Folder 73)
      Photographer if identified: Dave Roels
    - O.I.C. (Box A-91, Folder 74)
      Two prints are stuck together. Also two press releases.
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Bert Smith, Sharon Boykins
      Number of Prints: 44
    - Ojaleyl, Emonuel D.A. (Box A-91, Folder 75)
    - O'Jay, Eddie (Box A-91, Folder 76)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Miami-Metro Dept. of Publicity and Tourism, Charles Stewart, B. D. & B. Inc.
    - O'Jay, Eddie (Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 77)
    - O'Jay, Okay (Box A-91, Folder 78)
    - O'Jays, The (Box A-91, Folder 79)
      Also one velox and two press releases.
      Photographer if identified: James J. Kriegsmann, Allen Morgan
    - Oji, Aggrey K. (Box A-91, Folder 80)
    - O'Keefe, Paul T. (Box A-91, Folder 81)
    - Okin, Alexander J. (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 82)
    - Okorie, Omyema (Box A-91, Folder 83)
    - Okoronkwo, Chinyere Y. (Box A-91, Folder 84)
    - Okosun, Sonny (Box A-91, Folder 85)
    - Okoye, Godfrey (Bishop) (Box A-91, Folder 86)
    - Okpaku, Joseph (Box A-91, Folder 87)
      Photographer if identified: Mike Alexander
    - Okukwu, Odumegwu (General) (Box A-91, Folder 88)
    - Olajuwon, Hakeem (Box A-91, Folder 89)
    - Olatunji, Babalude (Box A-91, Folder 90)
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise, Dave Greene
    - Olatunji, Kwami (Box A-91, Folder 91)
    - Olatunji, Michael (Box A-91, Folder 92)
      Also one press release and one event flier.
      Photographer if identified: Bro. David McAdams, Bert Smith, Charles R. Blackwell, Bronx Community College Public Relations
    - Old Dracula (Box A-91, Folder 93)
    - Olden, George (Box A-91, Folder 94)
    - Oldham, Leon (Box A-91, Folder 95)
    - Olds, Victor (Box A-91, Folder 96)
    - Oliphant, Grassella (Box A-91, Folder 97)
    - Olita, Joseph (Box A-91, Folder 98)
    - Oliva, Sergio (Box A-91, Folder 99)
    - Oliva, Tony (Box A-91, Folder 100)
    - Olive, Betty (Box A-91, Folder 101)
    - Olive, Lewis (Major) (Box A-91, Folder 102)
      Photographer if identified: Wide World Photos, Ed Bagwell for News Voice International
    - Oliver, Albert G. (Box A-91, Folder 103)
      Note on folder: "(See Operation Crossroads Africa)."
      Photographer if identified: " "
    - Oliver, C. Herbert (Rev.) (Box A-91, Folder 104)
    - Oliver, Clinton F. (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 105)
    - Oliver, David (Box A-91, Folder 106)
    - Oliver, Don (Box A-91, Folder 107)
      Photographer if identified: Rappoport Studios
    - Oliver, Eugene Jr. (Box A-91, Folder 108)
    - Oliver, Fernando (Box A-91, Folder 109)
    - Oliver, Fred (Box A-91, Folder 110)
    - Oliver, C. Herbert (Rev.) (Box A-91, Folder 111)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Ace Creative Photos
    - Oliver, James (Box A-91, Folder 112)
    - Oliver, James (Box A-91, Folder 113)
      Also one magazine clipping.
    - Oliver, Kathy (Box A-91, Folder 114)
      Photographer if identified: Ornyere of Scorpio Beyond
    - Oliver, Leroy (Box A-91, Folder 115)
    - Oliver, Nate (Box A-91, Folder 116)
    - Oliver, Norman (Box A-91, Folder 117)
    - Oliver, Phyllis (Box A-91, Folder 118)
    - Oliver, Reggie (Box A-91, Folder 119)
    - Oliver, Richard (Box A-91, Folder 120)
      Photographer if identified: Sheedy & Long
    - Oliver, Russel (Box A-91, Folder 121)
    - Oliver, Ruth (Box A-91, Folder 122)
    - Oliver, Sandy (Box A-91, Folder 123)
    - Oliver, Sy (Box A-91, Folder 124)
    - Oliver, Sylvester Herman (Box A-91, Folder 125)
    - Oliver, Thelma (Box A-91, Folder 126)
      Photographer if identified: Yoscary, Bert Andrews, James Gilbert, Leaverton Associates, Friedman-Abeles
    - Oliver, Verne M. (Box A-91, Folder 127)
      Photographer if identified: Yorkville Photo Studio
    - Oliver, Vincent (Box A-91, Folder 128)
    - Oliver, W. B. (Box A-91, Folder 129)
    - Oliver, Wm. (Mr.) (Box A-91, Folder 130)
      Photographer if identified: L.O. Rogers
    - Olivieri, Antonio (Box A-91, Folder 131)
    - Ollie and the Nightingales (Box A-91, Folder 132)
      One typescript caption.
    - Olliverre, Cyril (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 133)
    - Ollivierre, Jeanne (Box A-91, Folder 134)
      One image cut from a magazine.
    - Olmedo, Luis A. (Box A-91, Folder 135)
    - Olowo, Bernadette P.A. (Box A-91, Folder 136)
    - Olson, Burray (Box A-91, Folder 137)
    - Olsten, William (Box A-91, Folder 138)
    - Olugebefola, Ademola (Box A-91, Folder 139)
    - Olugebefola, Ademola (Box A-91, Folder 140)
    - Olympio, Slyvanus (Box A-91, Folder 141)
      Photographer if identified: Pan American World Airways, Cecil Layne
    - Olympics, The (Box A-91, Folder 142)
      Photographer if identified: United Press International, Cecil Layne, Harris Photo, Pictorial Enterprise
    - Omeltchenko, William (Box A-91, Folder 143)
    - Omicron Chapter (Box A-91, Folder 144)
    - Omilami, Afemo (Box A-91, Folder 145)
      Photographer if identified: Anita Feldman Shevett
    - Onago + Muana (Box A-91, Folder 146)
    - 100 Black Men (Box A-91, Folder 147)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Ralph Cooper, Pictorial Enterprise, Aaron March, Allen Morgan
    - 100 Black Women (Box A-91, Folder 148)
    - 100 Black Women (Box A-91, Folder 149)
      Seven prints are stuck together. Also contains two velox prints.
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise, Bill Sparrow, Impact Photo, Ralph Cooper
    - 100 Black Women of Long Island (Box A-91, Folder 150)
      Photographer if identified: R. J. Capak
    - 114th Street (Rehabilitation) (Box A-91, Folder 151)
      Also one press release and one typescript leaf.
    - 125th St. (hanging out) (Box A-91, Folder 152)
    - 125th Street Medical Bldg. (Box A-91, Folder 153)
    - 127th Street Repertory Ensemble Co., The (Box A-91, Folder 154)
    - 100% Wrong Club (Box A-91, Folder 155)
    - One Last Look (Box A-91, Folder 156)
    - One Mo' Time (Box A-91, Folder 157)
    - One Potato, Two Potato (Box A-91, Folder 158)
    - O'Neal, Carolyn (Box A-91, Folder 159)
    - O'Neal, Frederick (Box A-91, Folder 160)
      Note on folder: "Also see: Anna Lucasta." Also two velox prints.
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise, James Gilbert, Free White and 21, David J. M. Robinson, Wagner International, Harris Photo
    - O'Neal, James Carroll (Box A-91, Folder 161)
      Photographer if identified: NYU
    - O'Neal, Ron (Box A-91, Folder 162)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, George West, Martha Swope
    - O'Neal, Sandra (Box A-91, Folder 163)
    - O'Neal, Shaquille (Box A-91, Folder 164)
    - O'Neal, Shirley (Box A-91, Folder 165)
    - O'Neal Twins (Box A-91, Folder 166)
    - O'Neal, Yvonne (Box A-91, Folder 167)
    - O'Neil, Carlton (Mr. + Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 168)
    - O'Neil, Max (Box A-91, Folder 169)
    - O'Neil, Melvin (Box A-91, Folder 170)
    - O'Neil, Wm. (Bishop) (Box A-91, Folder 171)
      Photographer if identified: David McAdams, Davogre Photo Studio
    - Onibokun, Thomas (Box A-91, Folder 172)
    - Onyeani, Chika (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 173)
    - Onyeani, Onika A. (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 174)
    - Onyekwere, Chiomo (Box A-91, Folder 175)
    - Onyema (Mr. + Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 176)
    - Ooro, Otieno (Box A-91, Folder 177)
      Photographer if identified: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
    - OPEC (Box A-91, Folder 178)
    - Opera (Box A-91, Folder 179)
      Photographer if identified: Martha Swope, Steve Gerardi, Dave Greene
    - Operation Breadbasket (Box A-91, Folder 180)
      Photographer if identified: Dave Greene, Harris Photo
    - Operation Better Block (Box A-91, Folder 180)
      Prints stapled together.
    - Operation Crossroads (Box A-91, Folder 181)
    - Operation Headstart (Box A-91, Folder 182)
      Note on folder: "See: Project Head Start."
    - Operation Helping Hand (Box A-91, Folder 183)
    - Operation Pride (Box A-91, Folder 184)
      Print has ms. note attached with paperclip.
    - Opus - 3 (Box A-91, Folder 185)
    - Opus 7 (Box A-91, Folder 186)
    - Oquendo, Angel (Box A-91, Folder 187)
    - Oral Caress (Box A-91, Folder 188)
    - Orchard, Thomas (Capt.) (Box A-91, Folder 189)
    - O'Reilly, Brian E.O. (Box A-91, Folder 190)
    - Orekie, Nelson (Box A-91, Folder 191)
    - Organization For Neighborhood Development (Box A-91, Folder 192)
      One booklet and one typescript leaf.
    - Organization of African Unity (O.A.U.) (Box A-91, Folder 193)
      Photographer if identified: Ethnic News Service/R. Taylor, Kwame Brathwaite
    - Original Preservation Hall Jazz Band (Box A-91, Folder 194)
    - Originals, The (Box A-91, Folder 195)
    - Tony Orlando and Dawn (Box A-91, Folder 196)
    - Orlons, The (Box A-91, Folder 197)
    - Orman, Roscoe (Box A-91, Folder 198)
      Photographer if identified: Doug Harris
    - Orner, Edward D. (Box A-91, Folder 199)
    - Ornstein, Walter (Box A-91, Folder 200)
    - O'Rourke, Edward (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 201)
    - O'Rourke, Maurice J. (Box A-91, Folder 202)
      Photographer if identified: Bro. David McAdams, United Press International
    - Orr, Alfonso (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 203)
      Photographer if identified: Ralph Cooper, Sleepy Hollow Studio
    - Orr, Dorothy (Box A-91, Folder 204)
      Also one velox print and two press releases.
      Photographer if identified: Pulman B.I.V., John Bisesi, James M. Mannas, Ralph Cooper, L. St. Clair Dummett, King Photographers, Bill Carter
    - Orr, Sally (Box A-91, Folder 205)
    - Orry, Isabelle W. (Box A-91, Folder 206)
      One image cut from magazine.
    - Orry, Thomas Francis (Box A-91, Folder 207)
    - Ortiz, Carlos (Box A-91, Folder 208)
      Photographer if identified: Jean-Daniel Noland
    - Ortiz, Delia (Box A-91, Folder 209)
    - Ortiz, Felix W. (Assemblyman) (Box A-91, Folder 210)
    - Ortiz, Gilbert (Dr.) (Box A-91, Folder 211)
    - Orton, Bobby's Teen-Aces (Box A-91, Folder 212)
    - Orvambo, Alalibo (Box A-91, Folder 213)
    - Osborn, Jewdyer (Box A-91, Folder 214)
    - Osborne, Christine (Box A-91, Folder 215)
      Photographer if identified: Phillip Kaye
    - Osborne, Darnley M. Jr. (Box A-91, Folder 216)
    - Osborne, Eltima (Box A-91, Folder 217)
    - Osborne, Ernest L. (Box A-91, Folder 218)
    - Osborne, Estelle (Box A-91, Folder 219)
      Photographer if identified: National League for Nursing
    - Osborne, Herman (Mr. + Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 220)
    - Osborne, Jason (Box A-91, Folder 221)
    - Osborne, Jeff (Box A-91, Folder 222)
    - Osborne, Joe (Dr. + Mrs.) (Box A-91, Folder 223)
    - Osborne, Kay (Box A-91, Folder 224)
    - Osborne, Thomas G. (Box A-91, Folder 225)
    - Oscar Peterson Trio, The (Box A-91, Folder 226)
    - O'Shea, Tessie (Box A-91, Folder 227)
    - Oshman, Louis (Box A-91, Folder 228)
    - Osibisa (Box A-91, Folder 229)
    - Osiris (Box A-91, Folder 230)
    - Osman, Rabin (Box A-91, Folder 231)
    - Killens, John O. (Box A-91, Folder 232)
    - New Orleans' Mardi Gras Indians (Box A-91, Folder 233)
      Note on folder: "featured in Expression '85 Festival of African Culture in the Americas."
    - Nelson, Charles Anthony (Box A-91, Folder 234)
      Photographer if identified: Official U.S. Navy Photograph
    - Osorio, Alicio (Box A-92, Folder 1)
    - Osorio, Belinda O. (Box A-92, Folder 2)
    - Ossie & Ruby "My Man Bovanne" (Box A-92, Folder 3)
    - Ostaro (Box A-92, Folder 4)
    - Osterer, David O. (Box A-92, Folder 5)
    - Osuagwu, Dandison M. Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 6)
    - Osuna, Raphael (Box A-92, Folder 7)
    - Oswald, Lee Harvey (Box A-92, Folder 8)
    - Oswald, Muriel (Box A-92, Folder 9)
    - OTB (Box A-92, Folder 10)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Bob Head,
    - Oteify, Gamal El Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 11)
    - Otero, Hilton (Box A-92, Folder 12)
    - "Othello" (Box A-92, Folder 13)
    - "Other Francisco" (Box A-92, Folder 14)
    - Othmer, Donald Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 15)
    - Otis, Clyde (Box A-92, Folder 16)
      Photographer if identified: Davidian Studio
    - O'Toole, Peter (Box A-92, Folder 17)
    - Richard Ottinger (Box A-92, Folder 18)
      Photographer if identified: United Press International/Dev O'Neill
    - Charlotte V. M. Ottley (Box A-92, Folder 19)
      Also 2 facsimile leaves.
    - Ottley, Jerome Peter (Box A-92, Folder 20)
    - Ottley, Peter J. (Box A-92, Folder 21)
      Also 2 velox prints. One print has staple through edge.
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise, Archer Associates, Acme Photograph Company, Ace Creative Photos, James Gilbert, Standard Flashlight Co., Harris Photo, Sam Reiss, Standard Studios, Wagner International Photos, King Photographers,
    - Otto-McLawler Trio (Box A-92, Folder 22)
    - Otto, Richard (Box A-92, Folder 23)
    - Otunnu, Olara (Box A-92, Folder 24)
      Photographer if identified: Sam Lwin
    - Ouattara, Dramane (Box A-92, Folder 25)
      Photographer if identified: Brathwaite International Photofeatures
    - Ouckama, Beverly (Box A-92, Folder 26)
    - Our Lady of Lourdes (Box A-92, Folder 27)
    - Ousley, Harold (Box A-92, Folder 28)
    - Ousley, Harold Quartet (Box A-92, Folder 29)
    - Outer, Delores (Box A-92, Folder 30)
    - Outlaw, Cynthia (Box A-92, Folder 31)
    - Outlaw, Daisy (Box A-92, Folder 32)
    - Outler, Gene (Box A-92, Folder 33)
    - "The Outsider" (see Ossie Davis) (Box A-92, Folder 34)
    - The Ovations (Box A-92, Folder 35)
    - Overby, Alice (Box A-92, Folder 36)
    - Overdiep, Jacques Mr. & Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 37)
      Photographer if identified: Ace Creative Photos, Wide World Photos
    - Overton, Bill (Box A-92, Folder 38)
    - Overton, Gloria (Box A-92, Folder 39)
    - Overton, Joseph J. (Box A-92, Folder 40)
      Also 13 velox prints.
      Photographer if identified: Tex Harris, Raymond P. Burton, James Campbell, Bro. David McAdams
    - Overton, Ruby (Box A-92, Folder 41)
    - Overton, Zella F. (Box A-92, Folder 42)
    - Ovington, Mary White (Box A-92, Folder 43)
    - Owa (Box A-92, Folder 44)
      Photographer if identified: Louis Draper
    - Owen, Ray Anthony (Box A-92, Folder 45)
      Photographer if identified: United Press International/Nick Pergola
    - Owens, Alvin (Box A-92, Folder 46)
    - Owens, Burgess (Box A-92, Folder 47)
    - Owens, Calvin E. (Box A-92, Folder 48)
    - Owens, Carl (Box A-92, Folder 49)
    - Owens, Cecilia (Box A-92, Folder 50)
    - Owens, Charles K. (Box A-92, Folder 51)
    - Owens, Clarence B. Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 52)
    - Owens, Douglas (Box A-92, Folder 53)
    - Owens, Estelle (Box A-92, Folder 54)
    - Owens, Frank (Box A-92, Folder 55)
      Also one velox print. 1 print mounted to matte.
    - Owens, Frederick (Box A-92, Folder 56)
    - Owens, George C. (Box A-92, Folder 57)
    - Herlema Owens (Box A-92, Folder 58)
    - Owens, Huston Jr. (Box A-92, Folder 59)
      Photographer if identified: Bob Lichtman
    - Owens, Jesse (Mrs.) (Box A-92, Folder 60)
      Photographer if identified: Curt Clemons, Shelley Brown, Pictorial Enterprise
    - Owens, Jerome (Box A-92, Folder 61)
    - Owens, Jimmy (Box A-92, Folder 62)
      Photographer if identified: Brent Owens, Bob Klein, Bill King
    - Owens, Joanna (Box A-92, Folder 63)
      Photographer if identified: Bunny Photo Studio, Rufus Merritt
    - Owens, Joyce (Box A-92, Folder 64)
      Photographer if identified: LeVon Studio
    - Owens, Major (Box A-92, Folder 65)
      Also 4 velox prints. 4 prints have staples through edge.
      Photographer if identified: Bill Hayes Photography, King Photographers, Hamilton Associates, David McAdams, Harris Photo, Clyde Jones, Dave Greene
    - Owens, Major (Box A-92, Folder 66)
      4 prints have staples through edge. 1 print has newspaper clipping taped to verso.
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise, Peterkin Photo, Harris Photo, Dave Greene
    - Maria Ramos Owens (Box A-92, Folder 67)
    - Owens, Melvin (Box A-92, Folder 68)
    - Owens, Odell (Box A-92, Folder 69)
      Photographer if identified: News Bureau, Antioch College
    - Owens, Paulette (Box A-92, Folder 70)
    - Owens, Richy (Box A-92, Folder 71)
    - Owens, Ronald Assemblyman (Box A-92, Folder 72)
    - Owens, Robert Rev. (Box A-92, Folder 73)
    - Owens, Robert Lee (Box A-92, Folder 74)
    - Owens, Robin (Box A-92, Folder 75)
    - Owens, Sam (Box A-92, Folder 76)
    - Owens, Shirley Ann (Mrs. Nelson Alston) (Box A-92, Folder 77)
    - Owens, Thaddeus (Box A-92, Folder 78)
    - Owens, Thomas F. Rev. (Box A-92, Folder 79)
    - Owens, Victor A. (Box A-92, Folder 80)
    - Owens, Willie (Box A-92, Folder 81)
    - Oxley, John (Box A-92, Folder 82)
    - Oxley, Lawrence (Box A-92, Folder 83)
    - Oxnan, G. Bromley (Bishop) (Box A-92, Folder 84)
    - Oyamo (Box A-92, Folder 85)
    - Oyedeji, Claleken Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 86)
    - Oyewole, Abiodun (Box A-92, Folder 87)
    - Oyewole, Abiodun (Box A-92, Folder 88)